It's yeah, like, like an experience where it's helped you learn, or like, like a positive experience, something that...
Audrey, you should just give me like a quick rundown of what you just did, because I have not read it yet.
Yeah.
Okay, we're all going out.
You guys will get in the room to yourself to just chat for the entire space, so yeah.
My bad.
I can't mute audio.
And then you're still on mute.
Andrew, you're on mute.
Mhm.
Okay, sorry about that.
Student.
Freaking Zoom calls, man.
Okay, I kind of talked about...
My *******.
how using it for model generation feels a little limiting because we can't directly edit those models. You could pull them into Onshape and you could add a little bit to them, but it doesn't work very well.
Understand.
Thank you.
Sorry, I feel like I'm a little echo right.
You are Sterling left his computer on.
Ohh.
So...
No.
No worries, though.
Whoops.
And then I agree with these points that it doesn't feel like our school or our skills are being utilized very well with this model generation. It would be way easier to just make a bunch of configurations on one cat model rather than having AI generate.
What is it?
5:35.
Open.
Did you?
Great reason.
everything having to tune every little structure that it creates.
OK, got you.
Okay.
And if making those models, you don't get to know those models as well, which means that it's harder to fix them if they're having issues or sometimes they have geometry errors, the mess of things that if a human had made them, it would have been fine because we wouldn't have done that.
Thank you.
Up the schedule, what is it?
right off the bat.
Oops.
Yeah, I'm really worried about the things where we've had a lot of AI generate a lot of what we're writing to the point where, like, I spent a lot of time writing my abstract and we ended up feeding it through AI. It added a bunch of sources and it...
Or.
No.
I have to.
Discuss.
Thank you.
One.
Like me afterward, and I didn't.
That was the way to go. I think we should have read our sources.
Cortana.
And yeah, that's about the helpful AI is that it can teach you things, and I think that's...
Okay.
Not cool.
Still be cool.
Okay.
The best use as a resource, and so it was really helpful for debugging into the 3D printer for me.
Yeah.
Thank you, Jorge.
Cortana.
Isn't it?
I feel like it, I feel like we're pushing a bit apart in other areas.
Okay.
What?
And yeah, that's about it.
What do you think?
I think it, I think it has been super good as like, I've been thinking of it as like an assistant.
Thank you.
What can you update?
in a lot of ways where like I use AI a ton for the lab and then for like my work and stuff just to like help myself stay organized. I have found that super useful.
I've also found it super useful to like be able to like write code and stuff with it, but when doing that, I think it's essential to like go back and actually understand what the code is doing. So like I'll use AI and generate a ton of code.
Oh
And then I'll go back through all of it and figure out what the heck it just did and what I want to change or what I need to optimize. Because it doesn't usually get it quite right. It might make it function, but it won't quite work exactly like I want or need it to. So I found that super interesting. I think the biggest thing is just recognizing that we're going to have...
Mhm.
AI forever. Like, there's no getting away from any of that. We really need to find a way to harness the power that it has to make us more like effective and efficient. If you don't know how to use it, you're going to fall behind. That being said, if that's all you use.
Search.
you're useless because anyone can use AI.
Wright.
That's kind of my thoughts. I don't know. So like, as far as using it in the lab, I guess I don't know. Like I use it a lot in the lab to like research stuff, just because it seems to do, it's a really quick way to like compare stuff that takes a lot of the grunt work out of it. And oftentimes it seems, yeah, like when I ask it to compare a mass amount of
Okay.
Beats.
Yeah, and it's good at finding information really fast, too, yeah.
3D model printers. Like it's really good at going to websites and pulling data and giving me a table that displays those results. And that saves me a ton of time, right? I don't have to go track down all that information. Like it's just given to me. I think it's right. You know what I mean? It's accurate. It pulled that from their site.
Sure.
When I ask AI to do other things, sometimes it'll like just completely hallucinate. When I ask it for like, how can I build this equation to optimize this process? It has no idea. And so it'll just spit something random. And if I run with it, like I am an idiot for trusting it completely and not trying to verify what it's doing.
Yes.
Yeah, I agree with that, especially with finding sources. I think it's important to go and read through those ourselves, or at least skin, you know, make sure that we're talking about the right things.
Yeah, and like just from like my short internship work experience that I've seen, it's everywhere. Like literally half of my day is working with AI to optimize a process.
Yes.
Like, thanks, thanks.
Oh, are you in an internship right now?
Yeah, I am.
Oh, nice. What are you doing?
Oh, like structural engineering stuff.
So not quite mechanical, but close enough, and it's a work experience. But I found it, I found it so, yeah, and I found it just so interesting, like how often they use Gemini and Clog and all these things. Like they are into it really deep. And so a lot of like my internship has been like finding
Main and Engineering.
the limits of AI for them and then say, hey, this is as far as we can push this.
I.
Like a lot of their tools are using AI to verify human work. And in the process, like they will be able to really cut down in like the amount of man hours and manpower that they need to do stuff because AIs are so effective at doing what I call the grunt work.
And so I think that's super interesting to see. It's like this isn't going anywhere. Like any business that's like wants to be strong is going to use this and then have someone verify it.
Bing.
So I think it's really interesting to see like what the world will become because all of a sudden you're, I don't know, I think it's really interesting. You just have to verify. You verify your sources, verify the work, verify the equations.
And once you kind of do that, like it got it gets the the math, it usually does pretty well on, especially where like a lot of the stuff I'm working with is kind of like our...
material, not material science, but mechanics of materials class. And so I think this applies to the lab too. It's like it does a lot of like easy grunt work very quickly and effectively. It just can't be allowed to make like core decisions or like core path or else it'll just belly flop.
Tools.
Mhm.
S.C.
Yeah, Gupta.
Yeah. And part of it is figuring out what is actually grunt work that it can manage too, right? Like, I mean, we spent months trying to get it to work with the CAD models and it's just not doing very well. And I think.
Alright, that was a rant.
I think that's okay because I think plenty of us actually enjoy doing CAD, you know.
And every CAD model is going to be different. It wouldn't be like recording data and sorting it and stuff like that's something that AI would be amazing for. But
Yeah.
Yeah, it's a little, yeah, that's one of the limits I think that AI has is it's not very good at generating those structures that we needed.
Yeah, like generating images and like spatial awareness, AI is very poor at. It does really well with like analyzing information and like things to do with like words and things like that. It does very good at image analysis, spatial analysis, things like that. It's not there yet.
Yeah.
It just, it doesn't, yeah, it doesn't live in the 3D world with us. It's all just code and stuff. And it can be super helpful for code. I mean, I've been a little more careful with generating so much code at once because often it'll come up with like a function or something that I haven't ever used before. And I'll be like, hey, what's that?
and then it takes a little more time, but then you're still learning with it, but often it can feel a little like you're trying to catch up to where AI is at and you're never going to get to that point, but you
You learn A lot.
But I think it's ultimately better writing my own code, because then I know exactly how it works and how I want it to be working.
Um...
Well, that's my opinion, if you have had lots of it last time.
One of those sub-team microphone, so we might, uh, I think we'll jump back together to...
I.
Yeah, let's jump to the next question. So...
Let's just kind of shift it over to lab culture. So like in the vertical cloud lab at BYU specifically.
What kind of things could we do? Like, what kind of conversations could we have to help out? Like, what kind of lab culture do we want? How do we set that kind of culture here, especially as new people come in, as people graduate, and then pass off the baton? You know, what does the lab culture look like there? So, regarding AI or just...
Janelle.
Yeah, yeah, and then I think it would be good to, in future, we'll do a break off, yeah, another break off, yeah, yeah, same people, yep, and report it too.
Sorry, you guys can keep going. Sorry for interrupting.
What do you think, Audrey?
Tag, you're it.
I don't know, I'm bad. I use AI a lot, like a lot, a lot.
As far as like the culture of it, I think that's very personal. I know like Xavier doesn't use it very much at all.
Yeah. I mean, do you feel, do you still feel like you're learning and that you're capable when you're using it though?
Yes and no.
Yes and no. There are times, kind of like what you're saying at the end, I literally will chase AI through like tons of code trying to figure out how it's doing, what it's doing. And at the end of the day, I come back to it and kind of just like look at it and it's like, well, it's working. I have a kind of a grasp of what I think it's doing.
I went to doing it. I don't know how that function exactly works. Like, I really don't know.
But it works, and I think I know kind of what it's doing. Can I, like, teach someone else what it's doing? No.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
And so I guess I trust it maybe too much in that sense.
That being said.
Like...
For me, it's kind of like the means to the end on like certain things. Like I would prefer not to be coding stuff my whole life. And so that's not something that intrigues me. And so maybe I am short circuit, like short circuiting my education in that aspect. But at the same time,
Okay.
It's something that I don't hope to be doing my whole life.
Gotcha. So you're not as worried about your coding skills because you don't see yourself using them very much.
If that makes sense.
Yeah, so like...
Like long term, yeah, I'm not as worried about that. Where I do spend like a lot more time understanding is things with like the 3D printers and like material science stuff. Like that's just information that I need to know like forever. And so like.
Okay.
Yeah.
When it comes to those things and I'm using AI, like even right now, like the amount of times I say, okay, walk me through and teach me what you just did.
And...
It will take, I will spend a ton of time going down that wormhole.
But I think it's still valuable and I think it helps me not shortly.
circuit, the educational experience. I think for me, I'm using AI mostly as like a way to get out of things that I don't really want to spend a lot of time on. If that makes sense. And I don't particularly see myself as like using them down the road.
Seth.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think that's useful. I've definitely had semesters where I feel like maybe too much on AI and that wasn't helpful for me for my learning. So I'm definitely a little more like, use it as little as possible. But like for things that it can easily automate, that's so, so beneficial.
I just...
I think we're on 2 opposites of the spectrum right now where you have you're relying on it like a lot right now and I'm like, I don't want to touch this stuff, but...
Yeah, and it's been hard because my internship, honestly, I thought it would be like showing me that like I need to not use AI as much. And then like I got here and I don't know if you're familiar with like Gemini notebooks and like Gemini gems and like all of those new features.
And.
Yeah, I am.
I spent probably 1/4 to 1/2 of my day every day using those tools and either trying to break them, trying to make them work quicker, or trying to find ways to like share them on like a larger scale. Like, that's all I'm doing. And then like, of course, going through as they work.
to like make sure they did the math right and they have the equations right. And you know what I mean, that like their reasoning isn't vlogged, but I don't think I've had, I mean, I've been here since May. I can count on one hand. I think the times the AI has gotten like the equation wrong for something like.
Right.
engineering related in the sense that like it performed a calculation that was just fault or it was just wrong.
You know what I mean? Like maybe four times.
Yeah.
And so...
This thing like me knowing how to do it those four times was incredibly helpful, but I think what it really has done is like really lowered the barrier to entry of like going in and deep diving into like specific things.
I don't know.
Okay, yeah, no, I can see that.
As far as like the culture though, like I think there has to be a balance. Like we have to use it. We can't say, hey, we are not going to touch that. That being said, I'm probably overusing it to the extent where like I'm...
Yeah.
West.
And probably under using it, so we just need to.
Yeah.
I will.
things. When I plus run and it runs and it works like it's supposed to, I don't ask a ton of questions and just if I and once I kind of like understand it a little bit.
Because I just don't, I don't know. It's interesting, very interesting. When it comes back to like school, like I feel like how I always used AI is like a better way where like I used it a lot to like study for things, but not necessarily to solve the exact problems I was solving, but maybe to solve.
Mhm.
Other problems, if it makes any sense, like just create additional problems.
Yeah, so you can see the workflow so that you can go do your own.
Yeah, but it was also very interesting in like, in my thermodynamics class, the teacher really encouraged AI usage, although he's no longer teaching here.
Who is the teacher?
I forgot, he was an older, bald man.
Yes.
Okay, so it wasn't Magleby then, right?
No, it wasn't Magleby, it wasn't Dillon, it was someone else. I recommend taking it from Doctor Dillon.
Mum.
I already took it, but thank you.
No, right? Oh, who'd you take it with?
I take it with Dillon.
Did you? Okay, yeah.
I like mine in the class, but it was a very interesting perspective on using AI to learn.
Yeah, where are you, where are you actually at in the program right now? Because I'm starting capstone, but it seems like I just took thermal, so.
I've got two more years still.
Okay.
I'm trying to do the program in four years, so I've got two more.
Like, this is the semester I'm taking, like, manufacturing and mechatron it, things like that.
Play music.
Manufacturing is awesome. Mechatronics.
It can be awesome. You're not allowed to use AI for mechatronics, so watch out.
No.
Yeah, but.
Ah, it can be so rewarding when something works, and when it doesn't work, it's like...
Oh, that's an interesting classical drawings.
Okay.
Manufacturing is so much fun though.
And enjoy that.
Yeah, MechEng.
What else were you in?
Hold up, I don't know offhand, like the writing class.
Mhm.
Yeah, that one's just a lot of work. That one's whatever.
What else?
Is it is it fun or is it just kind of busy work?
Parts of it are fun. Like, I mean, assuming every class has the same kind of flow, like the first project is like, you're going to write a set of instructions for someone and you need to make it really pretty easy to follow and stuff like that. And that's actually fun. And then you have like your assortment of
Yes.
that you have to do that are less fun, but you get them done and it's whatever.
Yeah, I feel like that's a good use of AI to like use it to write instructions, like give it a bunch of data and processes and then have it write the instructions and then just verify that it was good. I don't know.
And I'm switching over here, but it's also.
Bing.
Yeah.
Okay.
No, I say the.
Maybe not, though.
That's good. I mean, you also have to, everything you submit, you have to say what you used AI for and stuff like that. So just make sure, whatever you use it for, you're comfortable declaring to the professor.
Did you guys skip your video?
It's so interesting.